Cristian Alejandro López Freire

08/05/1987

34 years old.

Suecia E9-30 y República del Salvador, Cantón Quito, Pichincha,

Ecuador

0998173072

calopezf123@gmail.com



Experienced Senior Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Java, Javascript frameworks, databases, artificial intelligence, and software development methodologies. Strong engineering professional with a Master Data Management and Innovation focused in Information Technology.

Demonstrated certifications and understanding of JAVA technology, scrum methodology, and Amazon Web Services Knowledge. Solid management skills, an analytical thinker that consistently solves ongoing issues, and self-taught new software technologies.

Work Experience:

EPAM Systems. (Ago 2021 - now)

(Software / Technology)

Is an American-Belarusian company that specializes in product development, digital platform engineering, and digital product design. One of the world's largest manufacturers of custom software and consulting providers. The company's headquarters is located in Newtown, Pennsylvania, and its branches are represented in more than 30 countries.

Job description: Senior Software Engineer. I am working for client NORDSTROM creating affinities for customers in real-time.

Product: Nordstrom App and Web.

Used technologies:

Backend: Java 11, Spring Boot, Gradle.

Serverless: AWS Lambda, SQS, Bucket S3

Repositories: GitLab.

DevOps (Pipelines): Gitlab.

Databases: Postgres, Dynamo DB

SOLID principles, TDD, Design Patterns.

System Integration: REST, SQS, AWS Event bridge

SCRUM Methodology

Atlassian tools: JIRA, CONFLUENCE

Diners Club. (May 2018 – July 2021)

(Software / Technology)

Diners Club is a premium global brand with a rich heritage as the world's first charge card and is issued today in more than 200 countries and 70 local currencies.

Job description: Full Stack Developer. I worked creating a chatbot for Diners Club from the scratch. We create this product with microservices architecture design, deploying the app in AWS using EKS. We develop several business processes with artificial Intelligent of Watson from IBM. In the frontend we created some components from prototypes with UX and UI and those components were reusable with Vue.js. For the backend we used Springboot with Java 8 where we integrate to our CORE and focus in batch processes that the company has.

Product: CHATBOT Diners.

Used technologies:

Frontend: Vue.js, Javascript, CSS, Sass, Webpack, vue-cli, Vuetify, JWT, Vuex, Axios.

Backend: Java, Spring Boot, Spring Batch, EJB, JPA, Maven, Gradle.

Micro-services: Docker, Kubernetes.

Amazon Web Services: EKS, Containers, RDS, SNS, IAM, ECR, Cognito.

Repositories: GitHub.

Artifact Repositories: Nexus.

DevOps (Pipelines): Jenkins / Gitlab.

Artificial intelligence: Watson IBM.

Data bases: Postgres, Mongo DB

SOLID principles, TDD, design Patterns.

System Integration: Web Services. SOAP REST

SCRUM Methodology

Data analysis and reports: Quicksight AWS

Atlassian tools: JIRA, CONFLUENCE

Todo1 Services Inc. (Jun 2017 – Apr 2018)

(Software / Technology)

TODO1 is a company that provides e-business solutions to its shareholders, leading banking institution in Latin America

Job description: JAVA Developer.

Product: Sucursal Virtual Personas Grupo Bancolombia.

Used technologies:

Javascript, jquery, css, sass, bootstrap, Angular 6, Jsp, Spring, Struts, Struts2, JBOSS EAP, ORACLE DB.

Integration: Jenkins.

Repositories: Bitbucket.

Artifact Repositories: Nexus.

DevOps(Pipelines): ElectricFlow, Gitlab

Code checker: Sonar Qube.

Security: RSA Libraries.

Data bases: ORACLE, Postgres, Mongo DB.

Reports: JasperReports, BIRT.

System Integration: Web Services. SOAP REST

Look and Feel and UX changes.

SOLID principles, TDD, design Patterns.

Atlassian tools: JIRA, CONFLUENCE

Gestor sep 2014 – jun 2017

(Software / Technology) Ecuador

JAVA Senior Developer

Gestor develops high-tech solutions for international financial industries

Job Description: Develop and implementation of Gestor System on ISBAN – México (Querétaro) for Santander Bank México.

Technologies:

Backend/Frontend: JEE, JPA, EJB, JSF, Primefaces, Richfaces

Data bases: ORACLE, Postgres

Application server: Websphere y Jboss,

ORACLE FORMS y REPORTS

Atlassian tools: JIRA, CONFLUENCE

Saviasoft aug 2012 – sep 2014

(Informática / Tecnología)

Ecuador

JAVA Developer

Design and development of SOCIOEMPLEO Ecuador.

Technologies:

JEE, PRIMEFACES, POSTGRES, JASPER REPORTS.

Application server: Glassfish, Websphere y Jboss,

mar 2012 - aug 2012 **Lead Solutions**

Ecuador (Informática / Tecnología)

Software Developer

Technologies:

Oracle ADF, BD ORACLE, WEB SERVICES

ORACLE FORMS y REPORTS

jul 2009 - mar 2012 Inforsys Cia. Ltda. Ecuador

(Informática / Tecnología)

Computer Technician

Help Desk and software development.

Education:

Pontíficia Universidad Católica del Ecuador

Systems Engineer

OBS Business School

Master Data Management and Innovation.

Certifications:

ORACLE

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer Certification.

February 2014

INTERNATIONAL SCRUM INSTITUTE

Scrum Master Accredited Certification

November 2018

AMAZON WEB SERVICES

Aws Certified Cloud Practitioner

March 2019

Languages:

Spanish / English

Courses:

- Information Security TODO1
- Java Certification Program SAVIASOFT
- System Integration and Web Services GESTOR
- BDD noSQL HANDYTECH
- Java JEE, JSF, Primefaces, Richfaces GESTOR
- PLSQL y ORACLE FORMS GESTOR
- Oracle ADF Lead Solutions
- Apex Oracle Application Express Ecuador Oracle User Group.
- Angular 4 Platzi
- Agile Methodologies y SCRUM TODO1

Personal Information:

• Dirección: 12 de Octubre y Av. Francisco de Orellana

• Cel: (593) 998173072

• Identification: 1718891052

• Marital status: Single

• E-mail: calopezf123@gmail.com

References:

Name: Paola Bravo.

Position: CEO

Company: Saviasoft.

Cel: +593 98 775 0025.

Name: Carlos Almeida

Position: Product Manager

Company: Gestor

Cel: +593 98 449 0014

Name: Soledad Vinueza

Position: Product Owner

Company: TODO1

Cel: +593 992581514







THIS CERTIFIES THAT

Cristian López

IS RECOGNIZED BY
THE ORACLE CERTIFICATION PROGRAM AS AN

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 7 Programmer

March 10, 2014









SCRUM MASTER

ACCREDITED CERTIFICATION™

HEREBY WITH THIS CERTIFICATE WE ARE PROUD TO ENTITLE

LÓPEZ FREIRE CRISTIAN ALEJANDRO

AS SCRUM MASTER

IN TESTIMONY THEREOF, AFTER FORMAL EVALUATIONS WE ACKNOWLEDGE DEMONSTRATED KNOWLEDGE AND OUTSTANDING COMPETENCE OF OUR STUDENT AS SCRUM MASTER.

19 NOVEMBER 2018

DATE

AUTHORIZED SIGNATURE

61341912984848

AUTHORIZED CERTIFICATION ID

WWW.SCRUM-INSTITUTE.ORG

WWW.SCRUM-INSTITUTE.ORG



Cristian Lopez

has successfully completed the AWS Certification requirements and has achieved their:

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

Issue Date Mar 07, 2019

Expiration Date Mar 07, 2022 Waunen forergan

Maureen Lonergan

Director, Training and Certification

Validation Number Z8XVG0K1DM14Q4G3 Validate at: http://aws.amazon.com/verification